gis.com 2017-06-25

# Legal Information | Esri Privacy Statement

**Effective Date: January 12, 2017**

**Environmental Systems Research Institute, Inc. and its affiliate Esri Global, Inc., ("Esri") value the privacy of those who visit our websites and register for our software, services, and events.**

The Esri Privacy Statement ("Privacy Statement") covers our use, storage, sharing, and disclosure of personal information we collect through our websites, including [www.esri.com](https://www.esri.com/), [www.myesri.com](https://myesri.com/), [https://esricommunity.force.com](https://esricommunity.force.com/). It also describes your choices regarding use, access and correction of your personal information. Also please be aware that Esri has certain systems, services, platforms and environments as part of its product offerings and these product offerings support additional privacy assurances. For example, ArcGIS Online (arcgis.com), which has certifications or compliance requirements that are more restrictive and/or different than this Privacy Statement, with regard to collection or use of PII and other data types. In the event you attempt to access or contribute information or data to these systems, you should review this Privacy Statement as well as the information and the Esri Products & Services Privacy Statement Supplement at http://www.esri.com/legal/privacy-supplement. By using our websites or services, you authorize Esri to collect, use, store, share, and disclose your personal information as described in this Privacy Statement and any applicable addendums.

Please read the entire Privacy Statement before providing any personal information to us.

This Privacy Statement answers the following questions:

  * What personal information does Esri collect and receive?
  * Why is Esri collecting my personal information?
  * With whom does Esri share my personal information?
  * Is my personal information secured?
  * What are my privacy choices?
  * Can I access and update my personal information?
  * Will Esri modify its Privacy Statement?
  * How can I contact Esri regarding the Privacy Statement?

Esri complies with the U.S. – Swiss Safe Harbor Framework as set forth by the U.S. Department of Commerce regarding the collection, use, and retention of personal data from Switzerland. Esri has certified that it adheres to the Safe Harbor Privacy Principles of notice, choice, onward transfer, security, data integrity, access, and enforcement. To learn more about the Safe Harbor program, and to view Esri's certification, please visit <https://safeharbor.export.gov/swisslist.aspx>.

Esri participates in and has certified its compliance with the US-EU Privacy Shield Framework as set forth by the US Department of Commerce regarding the collection, use, and retention of personal information from European Union member countries. Esri is subject to the investigatory and enforcement powers of the Federal Trade Commission and Esri has certified that it adheres to the Privacy Shield Principles of Notice, Choice, Accountability for Onward Transfer, Security, Data Integrity and Purpose Limitation, Access, and Recourse, Enforcement and Liability. To learn more about the Privacy Shield program, please visit <https://www.privacyshield.gov/welcome> and to view Esri's certification, please visit <https://www.privacyshield.gov/list>.

Esri is responsible for the processing of personal data it receives, under the Privacy Shield Framework, and subsequent transfers to a third party acting as an agent on its behalf. Esri complies with the Privacy Shield Principles for all onward transfers of personal data from the EU, including the onward transfer liability provisions.

If you have an unresolved privacy or data use concern that we have not addressed satisfactorily, please contact our U.S.-based third party dispute resolution provider (free of charge) at <https://feedback-form.truste.com/watchdog/request>.

Under certain conditions, more fully described on the Privacy Shield website [<https://www.privacyshield.gov/article?id=How-to-Submit-a-Complaint>], you may invoke binding arbitration when other dispute resolution procedures have been exhausted.

**What personal information does Esri collect and receive?**

Personal information is information that can potentially identify you as a specific individual. It includes your name, company name, address, telephone number, email address, location, and billing information.

Esri websites and software installation may require registration with personal information to gain access to special services, authorization codes, license keys, or other features. This information will be used to authenticate users, provide support and deliver specialized services.

### Third-Party Information

If you use our referral service to tell a friend about Esri, we will ask you for your friend's name and email address. Esri will automatically send your friend a one-time email with an invitation to visit our website. Esri stores this information for the sole purpose of sending this one-time email and tracking the success of our referral program. Your friend may contact us at [privacy@esri.com](mailto:privacy@esri.com) to request that we remove this information from our database.

If you add a user to your ArcGIS Online service enterprise account, you may provide names and email addresses of your contacts. We will send your contacts a one-time email inviting them to create an account. Esri stores this information for the sole purpose of contacting such individuals as needed. They may contact us at [privacy@esri.com](mailto:privacy@esri.com) to request that we remove this information from our database.

In some instances, we may ask you to provide us with the name and phone number of an individual for the purpose of allowing Esri to contact that person in the event of an urgent matter. Esri stores this information for the sole purpose of contacting such individuals as needed. They may contact us at [privacy@esri.com](mailto:privacy@esri.com) to request that we remove this information from our database.

### Technologies

We and our partners use cookies and similar technologies to analyze trends, administer the website, track users' movements around the website, and gather demographic information about our user base as a whole. Users can control the use of cookies at the individual browser level.

### Log Files

We and our third-party tracking-utility partner gather certain information automatically and store it in log files. This information includes the Internet Protocol (IP) address, browser type, Internet service provider (ISP), and clickstream data. We do this to improve our services, marketing, analytics, or site functionality and to authenticate users.

**Why is Esri collecting my personal information?**

The personal information we collect is used by Esri and its service providers to:

  * Complete transactions, ensure appropriate legal use of licensed Esri software and services
  * Allow access to special services or other features
  * Analyze and resolve website and application problems,
  * Conduct market research and implement marketing strategies
  * Process orders and register software, data, or services
  * Provide notification to licensees about updates to Esri's and our affiliates' software, data, and services
  * Send marketing materials, Esri User Conference information, and newsletters
  * Respond to customer service requests and help provide technical and product support.

It will also allow users to sign up for a trial account, register for training or conferences, make requests that require a direct response, and order newsletters and other Esri publications.

Esri may use the mailing services of third parties that are authorized to use your personal information only for the benefit of Esri and our affiliates.

### Advertising

We partner with a third party to display advertising on our website or to manage our advertising on other sites. Our partner may use technologies such as cookies to gather information about your activities in order to provide you with advertising that is based on your browsing activities and interests. If you wish to not have this information used for the purpose of serving you with interest-based ads, you may opt out. If you are in the United States, go to <http://preferences-mgr.truste.com/>. If you are located in the European Union, go to [http://www.youronlinechoices.eu](http://www.youronlinechoices.eu/). Please note that this will not allow you to opt out of being served ads; you will instead receive generic ads.

### Social Media Features

Our website includes social media features such as the Facebook "Like" button, widgets such as the "ShareThis" button, or interactive mini programs ("Features"). These "Features" may collect your IP address, your browser type, also the specific page you are visiting on our website and set a cookie to enable the Features to function properly. Social media features and widgets are hosted either by a third party or directly on our website. Your interactions with the Features are governed by the privacy policy of the company providing them.

**With whom does Esri share my personal information?**

We use third parties such as a credit card processing company to bill customers for services, an email service provider to send out emails on our behalf, or technical service providers for customer support. When you sign up for our services, we will share your personal information only as necessary for the third party to provide that service. In addition, Esri may share your personal information within your organization, with third parties such as an Esri distributor, affiliate, or service provider within or outside the United States. Esri may also share or publish non-personal information, such as statistical data that provides information on how our users are using our software applications and services and how many people are visiting our websites. Our affiliates and vendors are also committed to protecting personal information as described in their privacy statements/policies. Under certain circumstances, we may remain liable for the acts of our third-party agents or service providers who perform services on our behalf for their handling of EU Personal Data that we transfer to them.

Esri will disclose your personal information when required to do so by law or in the good faith belief that such action is necessary to (1) conform to legal requirements, such as to comply with a subpoena or valid national security or law enforcement requests, or prevent fraud or imminent harm or (2) protect and defend the rights or property of Esri.

**Is my personal information secured?**

### Information Entered during Login or Placing Purchases

Esri maintains reasonable and appropriate security measures to protect EU Personal Data from loss, misuse, unauthorized access, disclosure, alteration, or destruction in accordance with the Privacy Shield. When you make a purchase through our website and sensitive information (such as login credentials or billing information) is entered, Esri encrypts the transmission of that information using transport layer security (TLS). If you have any questions about security on our website, you can visit [http://trust.arcgis.com](http://trust.arcgis.com/), or you can report a problem at <http://doc.arcgis.com/en/trust/security-concern/>. Additional information about Esri's security and privacy practices is available at <http://doc.arcgis.com/en/trust/security/arcgis-online-security.htm>.

### Information Posted on Esri's Blogs and Forums

Anytime you post on our blog or provide information, pictures, or any other type of personal information, data, or materials to forums, communities, or other social media platforms, please be aware that it will be publicly available and not subject to the terms of this Privacy Statement. Also, you may be posting using a third-party application, and we have no access to or control over such information. Please be aware that you are providing your personal information to these third parties and not to Esri. To request removal of your personal information from our blog, you can either log in to the third-party application and remove your posting/information or contact the appropriate third-party application provider. Your interaction with these features is governed by the privacy policy of the company providing them.

### Public Profiles

The profile you create will be publicly accessible unless otherwise indicated. You may change the privacy preferences of your profile through your account settings. Alternatively, you can contact us at [privacy@esri.com](mailto:privacy@esri.com) if you would like us to change the privacy settings of your profile.

### Esri Directories

If you have chosen to include yourself in an Esri directory such as Esri customers, User Conference exhibitor or attendee, distributors, partners or as part of MyEsri, your listing will be accessible within your organization and to all other contributors to those directories. You may change the preferences of your profile by logging in to update your certification record or contacting us at [privacy@esri.com](mailto:privacy@esri.com).

### Information Shared while Accessing Websites of a Third Party or an Esri Affiliate

Our website includes links to other websites with privacy practices that may differ from those of Esri. If you submit personal information to any of those websites, your information will be governed by their privacy policies.

**What are my privacy choices?**

If you submit personal information, Esri may contact you or send you marketing information, newsletters, or promotions about software or services. If you do not wish to receive this information, you may notify us by visiting <http://www.esri.com/unsubscribe> or following the unsubscribe instructions contained in the emails you receive.

Please provide us with your exact name and address as well as a description of the publication or type of mail you no longer wish to receive.

**Can I access and update my personal information?**

Upon request Esri will provide you with information about whether we hold any of your personal information. Esri will permit you to access, correct, or delete your information in our database by contacting [info@esri.com](mailto:info@esri.com) or by logging in to your account and making the appropriate changes. We will respond to all requests for access within a reasonable timeframe.

We will retain the personal information we process on behalf of our users for as long as needed to provide services to our users, comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes, and enforce our agreements.

**Will Esri modify its Privacy Statement?**

We may change this Privacy Statement or related system specific addendums from time to time. If and/or when Esri makes changes to this Privacy Statement, the updated version will be posted in place of this statement. If we make any material changes, we will notify you by means of an announcement here and on [http://trust.arcgis.com](http://trust.arcgis.com/) prior to the change becoming effective. We encourage you to visit [http://trust.arcgis.com](http://trust.arcgis.com/) periodically.

**How can I contact Esri regarding the Privacy Statement?**

If you have questions or complaints regarding our privacy practices or policy, please contact us at [privacy@esri.com](mailto:privacy@esri.com),or 380 New York Street, Redlands, CA 92373 USA, and identify the issue as such in your communication to Esri.
